http://www.rias.org.uk/about/privacy-policy

Any questions? +44 (0) 131 229 7545 | info@rias.org.uk |
RIAS on LinkedIn
Toggle navigation
About RIAS About RIASRutland Square HeadquartersCharter and Bye-LawsChaptersPresidentCouncil and CommitteesPolicies and ProceduresRIAS Strategy 2019-2024Honorary FellowsStaffNews from the RIASRIAS AwardsDoolan AwardUpcoming EventsDiaryConventionRIAS QuarterlyAnnual Reports and AGMsRIAS SketchbookRoll of HonourPrivacy Policy
For Architects OverviewMembershipStatement of Professional ConductConservation AccreditationSustainability AccreditationUsing the RIAS CrestSite SignboardsCPDInsurance ServicesJobs in ArchitectureSurveys
For Practices OverviewPractice ServicesPractice NotesPractice BulletinsPractice InformationAppointment DocumentsContract AdministrationCertificatesStandard LettersBest PracticeChartered PracticeChartered Practice Site Signboards
For Students OverviewBecoming an ArchitectScottish Schools of ArchitectureStudent AwardsJoining RIAS
Working with an Architect OverviewWhy use a Chartered Architect?Find an ArchitectArchitect in the HooseDirectory of Architectural PracticesA-Z of RIAS Architectural Practices in ScotlandBe Inspired… Architectural Projects in ScotlandConservation Accredited ArchitectsSustainability Accredited ArchitectsEnergy Design CertifiersDesign CompetitionsClient Advisory ServiceRIAS ConsultancyResolving DisputesBookshop
Join Now
Login
HomeAbout RIASPrivacy PolicyGrödians, Lerwick – Richard Gibson Architects© PhatsheepPrivacy Policy
This Privacy Policy sets out how the Royal Incorporation of Architects in Scotland (RIAS)
uses and protects any information that you give the RIAS when using any of our services,
including this website. We ask that you read this privacy notice carefully as it
contains important information on how and why we collect, store, use and share personal
information, your rights in relation to your personal information and on how to contact
us and supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.
The RIAS is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to
provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website,
then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.
When we collect and use personal information about you, we do so under the General Data
Protection Regulation (GDPR) which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom)
and we are responsible as "controller" of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.
Please do not send us any personal information if you do not want that information to be
used in this way.
The RIAS may change this Policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check
this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This Policy is
effective from 24th April 2018.What we collect
We may collect the following information:name and job titlecontact information including email addressdemographic information such as postcode, preferences and interestsother information relevant to customer surveys and/or offersWhat we do with the information we gather
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service,
and in particular for the following reasons:to provide and improve our services to youto process and respond to inquiriesto communicate with you periodically by bulletin/notices about new products,
special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the
email address which you have provided. You can change your preferences for receiving email
communications or postal. You can unsubscribe at any time in the footer of e-bulletins.internal record keepingfrom time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research
purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail.We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.We will hold the personal information for 6 years.Under the GDPR, most commonly, we will use your personal information where it is necessary:to perform the contract we have entered into with youto comply with a legal obligationfor our legitimate interests
Although this will be rare, in may be necessary for the RIAS to obtain your consent
from time to time for processing certain personal information. If so, we will seek your
consent for that in accordance with the GDPR rules.Keeping your personal information secure
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent
unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic
and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's
hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web
traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web
applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can
tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and
remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us
analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor
it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes
and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website by enabling us to monitor
which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access
to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept
cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer.
This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have
used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control
over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy
of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are
not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the
privacy statement applicable to the website in question.Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information
in the following ways:whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you
can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody
for direct marketing purposesif you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct
marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing
us at info@rias.org.ukWe will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties
unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal
information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may
find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.Your rights
Under the GDPR you have a number of important rights to access your personal information
free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:access your personal information which this Privacy Notice has described aboverequire us to correct any mistakes in your information which we holdrequire the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situationsreceive the personal information concerning you in certain situationsreceive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a
structure, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit this
data to a third party in certain situationsobject at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketingobject to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects
concerning you or similarly significantly affecting youobject in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal informationotherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstancesIf you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:write to our Data Protection Officer (DPO), Karen Stevenson at
RIAS, 15 Rutland Square, Edinburgh EH1 2BE or email info@rias.org.ukLet us have enough information to identify youLet us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving license or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill)Let know the information to which your request relatesHow to complain
We hope that our Data Protection Officer can resolve any query or concern
you raise about our use of your information.
The GDPR also gives you the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority,
in particular in the European Union state where you work, normally live or where any alleged
infringement of data protection laws occurred. The supervisory authority in the UK is the
Information Commissioner who may be contacted at https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
or 0303 123 1113.
The Royal Incorporation of Architects in Scotland, 15 Rutland Square, Edinburgh EH1 2BE
t: +44 0 131 229 7545
e:info@rias.org.ukRIAS Offices are open from 9am until 5pm, Monday to Friday.The RIAS values your privacy. View our privacy policy.Copyright © The Royal Incorporation of Architects in Scotland 2019.Charity Reference number: SC 002753
Registered Royal Charter No: RC 000483
Patron: HRH Prince Philip Duke of Edinburgh Hon FRIAS
